<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:contextHubPath="/etc/cloudsettings/default/contexthub"
        cq:contextHubSegmentsPath="/etc/segmentation/contexthub"
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2023-10-22T17:18:17.155+05:30"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="admin"
        cq:tags="[aem-avengers:aem-basics,aem-avengers:aem-basics/msm]"
        cq:template="/conf/aemavengers/settings/wcm/templates/page-content"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="MSM"
        sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/page"
        pageTitle="MSM"
        pwaCachestrategy="staleWhileRevalidate"
        pwaDisplay="standalone"
        pwaOrientation="any">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/container"
            layout="responsiveGrid">
            <container
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/container"
                layout="responsiveGrid">
                <title
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/title"/>
                <container
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/container"
                    layout="responsiveGrid">
                    <herobanner
                        jcr:created="{Date}2023-10-22T10:04:54.916+05:30"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2023-10-22T10:04:54.916+05:30"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/herobanner"/>
                    <text
                        jcr:created="{Date}2023-10-22T10:05:10.509+05:30"
                        jcr:createdBy="admin"
                        jcr:lastModified="{Date}2023-10-22T10:06:02.554+05:30"
                        jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        sling:resourceType="aemavengers/components/text"
                        text="&lt;p>MSM is a configurable framework for automating content deployment. Implementations often involve major portions of a website and span organizations and geographies. It is therefore highly recommended to plan MSM implementations as carefully as you plan your website:&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>Carefully&amp;nbsp;plan structure and content flows&amp;nbsp;before starting implementation.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>Keep the amount of live copies to a minimum.&amp;nbsp;Processing live copies is a resource-intensive task. The more live copies exist in your system the more performance can be affected: from processing internal live copy indexes, over live copy operations such as rollouts, to UI operations such as showing live copy relationships in the Sites Admin references rail. Best practice is to create live copies of sites or branches of a site, where the live copy relationships are inherited to pages in the site or branch. Avoid creating individual live copies for pages in a site or branch when the entire structure can be made into a live copy.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>Customize as much as necessary, but as little as possible.&amp;nbsp;While MSM supports a high degree of customization (for example, rollout configurations) typically the best practice for the performance, reliability and upgradeability of your website is to minimize customization.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>Establish a&amp;nbsp;governance&amp;nbsp;model early, and train users accordingly, to ensure success. A best practice from a governance point of view is to&amp;nbsp;minimize the authority that local content producers have&amp;nbsp;to allocate/connect content to other local users and their respective live copies. This is because un-governed, chained inheritances can significantly increase the complexity of a MSM structure and compromise its performance and reliability.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>Live Copy Sources and Blueprint Configurations&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>Keep in mind that a live copy can be created using either&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://experienceleague.adobe.com/docs/experience-manager-65/administering/introduction/msm-livecopy.html?lang=en#creating-a-live-copy-of-a-page&quot;>regular pages&lt;/a>&amp;nbsp;or a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://experienceleague.adobe.com/docs/experience-manager-65/administering/introduction/msm-livecopy.html?lang=en#creating-a-live-copy-of-a-site-from-a-blueprint-configuration&quot;>blueprint configuration&lt;/a>. Both are valid use cases.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>The additional benefits of using a blueprint configuration are that they:&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>Allow the author to use the&amp;nbsp;Rollout&amp;nbsp;option on a blueprint - to (explicitly) push modifications to live copies that inherit from this blueprint.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>Allow the author to use&amp;nbsp;Create Site; this allows the user to easily select languages and configure the structure of the live copy.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>Define a default rollout configuration for live copies that have a relationship with the blueprint.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>In the case that a blueprint configuration is not referenced, rollouts can only be initiated from the live copies themselves, essentially pulling content from source.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>When creating a new site with live copy, it is advantageous to create blueprint configurations to ensure the availability of the full MSM feature set.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>MSM can assist in the creation of multilingual websites in two ways:&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>When creating language masters.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>While MSM itself&amp;nbsp;does not provide content translation, it can be integrated with third-party translation connectors that do. Please note that:&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>MSM lets you cancel inheritance at the page- and/or component- level. This helps prevent overwriting translated content (from a live copy, with not-yet-translated content from a blueprint) on the next rollout.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>Some third-party translation connectors automate this management of MSM inheritances.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;p>Please check with your translation service provider for more information.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>An alternative approach for creating and translating language masters is to use language copies in conjunction with AEM’s out-of-the-box translation integration framework.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>&lt;p>When rolling out content from language masters.&lt;/p>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;li>For example, from the French language master to country-specific sites, such as France/French, Canada/French, Switzerland/French.&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/ul>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/li>&#xd;&#xa;&lt;/ul>&#xd;&#xa;"
                        textIsRich="true"/>
                </container>
            </container>
        </root>
        <cq:featuredimage
            jcr:lastModified="{Date}2023-10-22T17:18:17.140+05:30"
            jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="core/wcm/components/image/v3/image"
            altValueFromDAM="false"/>
    </jcr:content>
</jcr:root>
